caglecartoons.com 2019-07-13

# Privacy Policy | Cagle World

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally Identifiable Information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as described in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, credit card information, social security number, cookies or other details to help you with your experience.

When do we collect information?

We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order, subscribe to a newsletter, respond to a survey, fill out a form or enter information on our site.

Provide us with feedback on our products or services cookies, ads

How do we use your information?

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:  
<p style=”padding-left: 30px;”>• To personalize your experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.  
• To improve our website in order to better serve you.  
• To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests.  
• To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.  
• To quickly process your transactions.  
• To ask for ratings and reviews of services or products  
• To follow up with them after correspondence (live chat, email or phone inquiries)</p>  
How do we protect your information?  
<p style=”padding-left: 30px;”>• We do not use vulnerability scanning and/or scanning to PCI standards.  
• An external PCI compliant payment gateway handles all CC transactions.  
• We use regular Malware Scanning.</p>  
Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

We implement a variety of security measures when a user places an order enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of your personal information.

All transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our servers.

Do we use ‘cookies’?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

We use cookies to:  
<p style=”padding-left: 30px;”>• Help remember and process the items in the shopping cart.  
• Understand and save user’s preferences for future visits.  
• Keep track of advertisements.  
• Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third-party services that track this information on our behalf.</p>  
You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Since browser is a little different, look at your browser’s Help Menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If users disable cookies in their browser:

If you turn cookies off it will turn off some of the features of the site.

Third-party disclosure

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information unless we provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release information when it’s release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property or safety.

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

Third-party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

Google

Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by Google’s Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en  
We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website.

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy.  
<p style=”padding-left: 30px;”>We have implemented the following:

• Remarketing with Google AdSense  
• Google Display Network Impression Reporting  
• Demographics and Interests Reporting  
• DoubleClick Platform Integration</p>  
We, along with third-party vendors such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.

Opting out:

Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative Opt Out page or by using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

California Online Privacy Protection Act

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require any person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting Personally Identifiable Information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals or companies with whom it is being shared. – See more at: http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf

According to CalOPPA, we agree to the following:  
Users can visit our site anonymously.  
Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum, on the first significant page after entering our website.  
Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can easily be found on the page specified above.  
<p style=”padding-left: 30px;”>You will be notified of any Privacy Policy changes:

• On our Privacy Policy Page  
Can change your personal information:  
• By emailing us  
• By calling us  
• By logging in to your account</p>  
How does our site handle Do Not Track signals?  
We honor Do Not Track signals and Do Not Track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?  
It’s also important to note that we allow third-party behavioral tracking

COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under the age of 13 years old, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, United States’ consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online. We do not specifically market to children under the age of 13 years old.

Fair Information Practices

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:  
• We will notify the users via in-site notification

We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle which requires that individuals have the right to legally pursue enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

CAN SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

We collect your email address in order to:  
<p style=”padding-left: 30px;”>• Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions  
• Process orders and to send information and updates pertaining to orders.  
• Send you additional information related to your product and/or service  
• Market to our mailing list or continue to send emails to our clients after the original transaction has occurred.</p>  
To be in accordance with CANSPAM, we agree to the following:  
<p style=”padding-left: 30px;”>• Not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.  
• Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.  
• Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.  
• Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.  
• Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.  
• Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.</p>

To Users Resident in the European Economic Area: This Privacy Policy will govern use of your personal information if you choose to use any of the Cagle Cartoons, Inc. Web sites, services and applications. Your specific rights as European Union data subjects (“EU Data Rights”) are addressed below.

Privacy Rights of Users in the European Economic Area (EEA)

Under the EU General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (“GDPR”), effective as of May 25, 2018, European Union data subjects are entitled to certain specific rights with respect to processing of their personal data.

Under the GDPR, in certain circumstances, you have the right to:  
<p style=”padding-left: 30px;”>• Request access to your personal information;  
• Request the correction of inaccurate or incomplete personal information;  
• Request that your personal information be erased;  
• Object to the processing of your personal information, including processing for direct marketing purposes;  
• Request that the processing of your personal information be restricted;  
• Request that you receive your personal information in order to transfer it to another data controller;  
• Withdraw at any time your consent to the use of your personal information;  
• Make a complaint to an EU Data Protection Authority where you believe that we have not complied with our obligations under this Privacy Policy or applicable European data protection law (including the GDPR); and  
• We will not transfer your personal information to third parties located outside of the EEA without taking steps to ensure adequate protection under the GDPR. If a third party is located in a country not recognized by the EU Commission as providing an adequate level of protection, we will use appropriate measures, such as entering into standard contractual clauses, approved by the EU Commission, to protect your personal information.  
You may exercise any of the above rights by contacting us at privacy@cagle.com or writing to us at the address at the bottom of this page.</p>  
For Non-EU International Users

Cagle Cartoons, Inc. is a California Corporation that is owned and operated in the United States. We have developed policies and implemented practices to comply with regulations in the European Union and in Canada. If you are located anywhere else outside of the United States, please be aware that information we collect will be transferred to, processed, and stored in the United States. The data protection laws in the United States may differ from those of the country in which you are located, and your personal information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in the United States according to laws of the United States. By using Cagle Cartoons, Inc. Web sites, services and applications, or by providing us with any information, you consent to this transfer, processing, and storage of your information in the United States. You are also consenting to the application of United States federal and California state law in all matters concerning the Site and this Privacy Policy.

Your Consent to Transfer Your Personal Information to Our Website.

If you are visiting our site from outside the United States, please be aware that your information will be transferred to, processed, and stored in the United States where our servers and central databases are located. By your agreement to use our sites and services, and by your acceptance of this Privacy Policy, you consent to such transfer of your personal information for use in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

How Long We Store Your Information.

Unless we have deleted your information in accordance with your request pursuant to this Privacy Policy, we will retain your information for so long as your account is active or as needed to provide you any of our services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information, please email us at privacy@cagle.com or call us at (805) 969-2829. We will retain and use your information to the extent necessary to comply with applicable laws, resolve disputes, or enforce our contractual rights.

Disputes

If you choose to visit Cagle Cartoons, Inc. Web sites and/or use our services, your visit and any dispute over privacy, excluding matters that are required to be resolved before European data protection authorities pursuant to European Union data protection law (including the GDPR), is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use including limitations on damages, resolution of disputes, and application of the laws of the United States and the State of California.

No Rights of Third Parties

This Privacy Policy does not create rights enforceable by third parties or require disclosure of any personal information relating to users of the website.

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email us at privacy@cagle.com or follow the instructions at the bottom of each email and we will promptly remove you from all correspondence.

Contacting Us

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may contact us using the information below.

Cagle Cartoons, Inc.  
PO Box 22342  
Santa Barbara, CA 93121 USA

editor@cagle.com  
(805) 969-2829

This policy applies to all of our Cagle Cartoons, Inc. operated Web sites, including: CagleWorld.com, CagleNews.com, Caglecartoons.com, Politicalcartoons.com, Cagle.com, CaglePost.com, DarylCagle.com and any other sites owned and operated by Cagle Cartoons, Inc.

If you feel that this site is not following its stated information policy, you may contact us at the above phone number.

Last Edited on May 24, 2018
